## **NISHANT CHAUDHARY**

+91-8477026477 chaudhary.nishant98@gmail.com

# **Summary**

 Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in Big Data stack, specifically PySpark, Python, AWS and Microsoft Azure, passionate about building products that have the potential to benefit millions by applying in-depth knowledge of Data Structures and Algorithms.

# **Employment**

Software Engineer Tekion Corp Dec 2021 - Present

- Working as a Data Engineer in the Data Platform team.
- Reduced S3 costs by 40% by optimising Apache Spark and Delta Lake.
- Optimised the raw data ingestion improving the ingestion time by 50%.
- Designed and implemented change data capture-based ingestion pipelines improving the data quality by 10% and delay by 30%.
- Led the schema registry project which gave one view of 90% of the tables' schema present in the data warehouse and source databases.

## **Specialist Programmer**

#### **Infosys Limited**

October 2020 - December 2021

- Key responsibilities included implementing and managing the data flow pipelines, ingestion modules and metadata store.
- Designed and implemented a unified data pipeline to ingest 60+ datasets accounting for more than 30% of the total load.
- Designed data flow and implemented validations/transformations for datasets as huge as 1.5 million records.
- Improved efficiency by up to 15% by creating a generic script that reduces the effort to perform similar tasks.

# Languages and Technologies

- Programming Languages Python, Java (basic)
- Big Data Frameworks Apache Spark, Hadoop, Spark Streaming, Delta Lake
- Cloud Services AWS, Microsoft Azure
- Database PostgreSQL
- Others Git, Jira, Augmented Reality, Data Structures and Algorithms

## **Education**

### Dehradun, India

## **Graphic Era University**

July 2016 - June 2020

- Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering with CGPA: 8.59/10
- Main coursework Data Structures, Design and analysis of Algorithms, Database Systems, Operating Systems

## **Projects**

#### **Augmented Reality Android App**

July 2019 - April 2020

• Developed an Augmented Reality based food ordering application for Android that helps the user visualize a 3D model of the food item in the real world. The application is live on Google Play (link).

Instagram Filter July 2020

• Created an Instagram game filter/effect in Spark AR Studio that can be played by two players simultaneously. Handled the patch editor, scripting, coding and overall logic of the project (link).

#### **Achievements and Certifications**

- Finalist of Spark AR Open Program by School of Innovation India from Facebook.
- Qualified the prestigious examination of GATE (CS) 2020 with a score of 96.5 percentile.
- Certifications Microsoft certified Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900), Microsoft certified Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900), Infosys certified Software Programmer, Infosys certified Global Agile Developer